Welcome. In the last lecture, we set up an idle to climb montage and now by pressing
欢迎。在上一节课中，我们设置了一个从空闲到爬升的蒙太奇，现在通过按下
the climb action key, we'll be playing that montage and a callback function will be fired
攀登动作键，我们就会播放这个蒙太奇，一旦蒙太奇结束，一个回调函数就会启动
once a montage has ended. And starting from this lecture, we'll look at how we can play
一旦蒙太奇结束，一个回调函数将被触发。从这个讲座开始，我们将研究如何在我们的游戏中播放
the correct animation when we are inside of the climb state. And I like to take care of
当我们处于爬升状态时如何播放正确的动画。而我喜欢先处理好
the coding part first. So I'm going to close my project and instead of this custom moving
编码的部分。所以我将关闭我的项目，而不是这个自定义的移动
component, I'm going to scroll down to this own climb montage ended. So when this function
组件，我将向下滚动到这个自己的爬升蒙太奇结束。所以当这个函数
is fired, I'm going to first delete this debug line. We'll know what's the montage that's
被触发时，我将首先删除这个调试行。我们将知道什么是蒙太奇的
currently ending. And for that, we can do an if check in here. So if this montage is
目前正在结束。为此，我们可以在这里做一个if检查。所以如果这个蒙太奇是
equal to idle to climb montage, then that means we want to enter the climb state. So
等于idle to climb montage，那么这意味着我们要进入爬升状态。所以
in here, I'm going to call the function start climbing. All right, this should take care
在这里，我将会调用函数start climbing。好的，这应该能处理好
of transitioning us from idle to climb. And next thing I'm going to go back to this character
将我们从空闲状态过渡到爬升状态。接下来，我要回到这个角色的
in an instance. Inside of it, we'll need another variable. So I'm going to copy this
在一个实例中。在它的内部，我们需要另一个变量。所以我将复制这个
U property, paste it in here. And I'm going to create a new variable. So this variable
U属性，把它粘贴到这里。然后我将创建一个新的变量。所以这个变量
I'm going to call it b is climbing. And same as above, create a function definition is
我将把它叫做b，是攀升的。和上面一样，创建一个函数定义是
going to be void. I'm going to call get is climbing. And I'm going to create a function
将会是无效的。我将调用get is climbing。然后我将创建一个函数
definition, place the function at the bottom of this CPP file. So paste it in here. First
定义，把这个函数放在这个CPP文件的底部。所以把它粘贴在这里。首先
thing in case I forget, I'm going to call the function inside of this update animation.
以防我忘记，我将在这个更新动画中调用这个函数。
I'll paste it in here. And for this function, we simply need to query our custom movement
我把它粘贴在这里。对于这个函数，我们只需要查询我们的自定义运动
component and access the function is climbing and assign the value of it to this b is climbing.
组件，然后访问 "正在爬升 "这个函数，并把它的值赋给 "正在爬升"。
All right, that's all we need to do inside of code. I'm going to compile first. I have
好了，这就是我们在代码里面需要做的所有事情。我先来编译一下。我有
a successful compile. I'm going to launch my editor back. Go back to my editor. I'm
成功的编译。我将启动我的编辑器回来。回到我的编辑器。我将
going to go inside of this raw folder. Then I'm going to duplicate this hanging idle.
去这个原始文件夹里面。然后我将复制这个悬挂的闲置。
And I'm going to call this one climbed idle underscore adjusted and place this animation
我将把这个攀升的空闲称为调整后的空闲，并把这个动画放在调整后的文件夹里。
inside of this adjusted folder, select move here. Then I'm going to go back to this climb
在这个调整后的文件夹中，选择移动这里。然后我将回到这个爬升
system, open the ABP. And inside of it, I'm going to double click to open this full body.
系统，打开ABP。在它里面，我要双击来打开这个全身。
So once we finish playing the montage, we'll need to transition to the climb idle state.
因此，一旦我们完成了蒙太奇的播放，我们将需要过渡到爬升的空闲状态。
And for that, I'm going to search for it. So it's called climbed idle and drag out this
为此，我将搜索它。所以它被称为爬升空闲，拖出这个
animation, place it in here and delete this adjusted. And I'm going to drag out a pin
动画，把它放在这里，然后删除这个调整后的动画。然后我将拖出一个引脚
connected to here. And for this transition rule, double click to open it. I'm going to
连接到这里。对于这个过渡规则，双击来打开它。我将会
access the variable that we just created. So hold down control, drag it out, connect
访问我们刚刚创建的变量。所以按住控制键，把它拖出来，连接到
it to here. So if it's climbing is true, we'll enter this state. All right, this should work
它连接到这里。所以，如果它的爬升为真，我们将进入这个状态。好了，这应该可以
for now. Let's test it out. So come back to my level. I'm going to click play, then go
现在。让我们测试一下。所以回到我的水平。我将点击播放，然后进入
to the surface, press F and you can see we are inside of the climb idle state. And I'm
到表面，按F，你可以看到我们是在爬升空闲状态下的。而且我相信你能注意到
sure you can notice that the position of this animation does not align with our capsule.
你肯定能注意到这个动画的位置与我们的太空舱不一致。
So that means we'll need to manually adjust this idle animation. So I'm going to make
所以这意味着我们需要手动调整这个空闲动画。所以我将会对它进行
some adjustments on it. Go back to this animation, go inside of adjusted, double click to open
对它进行一些调整。回到这个动画，进入调整后的动画内部，双击来打开
this climb idle. And I'm going to click pause, move to the first frame and go to the back
这个爬升空闲。我将点击暂停，移动到第一帧，然后转到后面的
of it. So this is the current offset of this animation. And in order to move the body of
它的后面。所以这就是这个动画的当前偏移。为了移动这个角色的身体
this character, there are two in editor solutions that we can use. So first we can directly
为了移动这个角色的身体，我们可以在编辑器中使用两种解决方案。所以首先我们可以直接
adjust the root bone or we can adjust the pelvis. But since later we'll need to use
调整根骨或调整骨盆。但由于后来我们需要使用
control rig to help us to place our hands and the feet on the surface, adjusting pelvis
控制设备来帮助我们将手和脚放在表面上，调整骨盆
here will mess up with the bone data. So instead I'm going to directly adjust the root bone.
这里会弄乱骨头数据。所以我打算直接调整根骨。
Since we're not using the root motion here, this solution should work just fine. All right.
由于我们在这里没有使用根部运动，这个解决方案应该可以正常工作。好的。
After having the root bone selected, I'm going to press W. I'm going to drag it down a little
选定根部骨骼后，我将按W键。
bit to somewhere near here and click this add key and click save. All right, go back
到这里附近的某个地方，然后点击这个添加键并点击保存。好了，回到
to my level. I'm going to press play again, go to the surface, press F. The height of
回到我的水平。我将再次按播放键，到表面，按F。
it is kind of too low. I'll need to lift this up a little bit. So go back to it and move
它的高度有点太低了。我需要把它抬高一点。所以回到这里，把
this root bone up to somewhere near here and press add key again. All right, then press
这根骨头移到靠近这里的地方，然后再按添加键。好的，然后按
play, press F. Yeah, something like that. And now this idle animation aligns with our
播放，按F。 对，就这样。现在这个空闲的动画与我们的
capsule perfectly. And next thing I'd like to take care of. So if I press F now, we are
胶囊完美对齐。接下来我想处理的事情是。所以如果我现在按F，我们就
no longer inside of the climb state, but we are still in this climb idle animation. I
不再处于爬升状态，但我们仍然处于爬升的空闲动画中。I
don't want that. So go back to this climb system folder, double click to open this ABP
我不希望这样。所以回到这个爬升系统文件夹，双击打开这个ABP
again. So this climb idle should be able to transition to a new state. I'm going to call
再次打开。所以这个爬升空闲应该能够过渡到一个新的状态。我打算把它叫做
this one climb drop. And the transition rule here should be when this is climbing is false.
这一个爬升下降。而这里的过渡规则应该是当这个爬升是假的。
So use the not Boolean connected to here and go back to full body. Now we'll need to fill
所以使用连接到这里的not Boolean，然后回到全身。现在我们需要在这里填充
in some animation in here. So go back to my content browser. Inside the raw folder, I'm
在这里的一些动画。所以回到我的内容浏览器。在原始文件夹中，我将
going to duplicate this brace hang drop and I'm going to call this one climb drop adjusted
我将复制这个支架悬垂，我将把这个攀登悬垂称为调整的
and move it to the adjusted folder and double click to open it. Click play. So this is its
并把它移到调整后的文件夹中，双击打开它。点击播放。所以这是它的
animation. And I think right now it's too long. I don't need it to be this long. I'm
动画。我认为现在它太长了。我不需要它这么长。我准备
going to trim a few frames from it. So I think right after our character released the hands
我打算从它身上剪掉几帧。所以我想在我们的角色松开手之后
somewhere near here, about 17 frames. Right. I'm going to right mouse button click and select
在这里附近的某个地方，大约17帧。对。我将鼠标右键点击并选择
this remove from frame 18 to 51 and same as our idle animation, we'll need to adjust the
从第18帧到第51帧删除，和我们的空闲动画一样，我们需要调整一下
position of it just to have a comparison in here. I'm going to select this climb idle,
我们需要调整它的位置，以便在这里做个比较。我将选择这个爬升空闲、
hold down shift on my keyboard, double click to open it. So this could allow us to open
按住键盘上的shift键，双击来打开它。所以这可以让我们打开
two animation windows by default. If we don't hold down the shift key, we'll be only able
两个默认的动画窗口。如果我们不按住shift键，我们就只能
to open one animation window. So I'm going to click pause in here, go to the first frame.
打开一个动画窗口。所以我要在这里点击暂停，转到第一帧。
So this is the initial height of this idle animation and go to this climb drop. Having
所以这是这个空闲动画的初始高度，然后转到这个爬升下降。在选择了
the root bone selected, I'm going to drag it down to somewhere near here. Yeah, I think
选择了根部的骨头，我要把它拖到靠近这里的地方。是的，我认为
they're close enough. Maybe a bit lower. They don't need to be perfectly aligned. Just try
它们已经足够接近了。也许再低一点。它们不需要完全对齐。只是尽量
to be as close as possible. And I'm going to click this add key. All right. Go back to
尽可能的接近。然后我将点击这个添加键。好的。返回到
my animation blueprint and go inside of this climb drop, search for the animation climb
我的动画蓝图，并进入这个攀登下降的内部，寻找攀登下降的动画
drop and put it in here and go back to full body. So our climb drop should be able to
并把它放在这里，然后回到全身。因此，我们的爬升下降应该能够
transition to this for loop and our for loop can transition us back to this ground locomotion.
过渡到这个for循环，而我们的for循环可以过渡到这个地面运动。
And for that, I like to create another state alias. So right mouse button click to add
为此，我喜欢创建另一个状态别名。所以，鼠标右键点击来添加
state alias. I'm going to call this one alias underscore for loop and take this for loop
状态别名。我将把这个别名称为下划线for loop，并把这个for loop
in here, connect this pin to here. And for this transition rule, I'm going to change
在这里，把这个引脚连接到这里。对于这个过渡规则，我将把它改为
this to automatic rule and change this mode to cubic. And let's test this out. I'm going
将其改为自动规则，并将其模式改为立方。让我们测试一下这个。我将
to press compile and go back to my level, press play, go to the surface, press F. So
按编译，回到我的关卡，按播放，到表面，按F。
we are inside of the climb state, press F again and we can transition back to this ground
所以我们现在处于爬升状态，再按一次F，我们就可以过渡到地面运动。
locomotion. So I'm going to press F again and this time I'm going to go to somewhere
运动。所以我将再次按F，这次我将去某个地方
near here and press F. Try again. So I think the height of this climb drop is lower than
在这里附近，按F键，再试一次。所以我认为这个爬升下降的高度要比
this idle animation. So we'll have some sort of sliding happening. I'm going to fix that.
这个空闲动画。所以我们会有一些滑动的情况发生。我要去解决这个问题。
So go to this climb drop. I'm going to move it up a little bit to somewhere near here.
所以去看这个爬升下降。我要把它往上移一点，移到这里附近。
Click this add key and try again. Now move it to here, press F. All right. This looks
点击这个添加键，再试一次。现在把它移到这里，按F，好了。这看起来
natural enough. Yeah, looking pretty cool. So these are the new states that I add in in
够自然。是的，看起来非常酷。所以这些是我在动画蓝图中加入的新状态
my animation blueprint. There's nothing too complicated for the logic part, but just be
我的动画蓝图。在逻辑部分没有什么太复杂的东西，但只要耐心等待动画的调整。
patient with the adjustments for the animations. After you have the transitioning animation
对动画的调整要有耐心。在你准备好过渡动画后
ready, next thing that we need to take care of will be adding the climb locomotion to
准备好后，我们需要处理的下一件事是将爬升运动添加到
our animation blueprint and we'll look at how we can do that in the next lecture. So
我们将在下一节课看看如何做到这一点。所以
feel free to refer back to the video if you need help and I'll see you in the next lecture.
如果你需要帮助，请随时参考视频，我们在下一讲再见。
[music]
[音乐]